Preliminary Inventory of the Lee Edwards Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound recordings (Box 1, 8-11, 152-153, 163, 213-221, 330)
  - Lee Edwards interviews William F. Buckley, Jr. on 12 Dec 1996, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Edwards interviews William F. Buckley, Jr., about the conservative movement of the past fifty years, after briefly discussing Ed Feulner. Buckley says Reagan was the most important conservative figure over that time. He cites the following as turning points for the movement: Taft-Hartley, the conviction of Alger Hiss, Supreme Court court decisions, the election of Reagan, the fall of the Berlin Wall, and Bush on taxes. On the similarities and differences of Edwards' focal four figures (Taft, Goldwater, Reagan, Gingrich), Buckley argues Goldwater and Reagan were not that similar outside of being crowd pleasers. He also believes it is too early to speak about Gingrich. Other topics they cover are National Review, libertarianism vs. conservatism and the possibility of a purely-libertarian president, and the impact of computers are people's papers and records. Edwards concludes the conversation by saying the reason why conservatives won and liberals lost is that they rallied around two concepts: (1) communism was evil, and (2) the welfare state was out of control. Buckley adds a third point, a belief in a transcendent god.
  - Lee Edwards interviews William F. Buckley, Jr. on 13 Apr 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003583
    Edwards interviews Buckley about Barry Goldwater, Conscience of a Conservative, and the 1964 campaign.
  - Lee Edwards interviews William F. Buckley, Jr. on 31 Oct 1994, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003379
    The interview is mostly a discussion of religion in America. Topics cover include why there were so many Catholics in opposing communism, the effect of the Religious Right and whether it is a good thing or not, separation of church and state, prayer in schools, abortion, the Pope, if Buckley ever wanted to be a priest, Dan Quayle, and the difference between Buckley’s libertarianism and the Ayn Rand/Murray Rothbard-style libertarianism.
    Aside from religion, Edwards asks if the country should be teaching values to its young, and he also asks if Buckley has a candidate for the 1996 election.
    The second side of the original microcassette contains an interview with his brother. They focus on growing up with Bill and other family matters.
  - Lee Edwards interviews William Peterson on 25 Sep 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004815
  - Lee Edwards interviews William Regnery on 4 Jan 2002, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004828
  - Lee Edwards interviews William Rusher on 6 Nov 1973, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004835
  - Remarks of the President during an interview with Conservative Digest, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004821
    Lee Edwards interviews President Reagan about the 1984 campaign.
  - Sound recording of a speech by Bill Bennett concerning the 1996 election and interview about the Heritage Foundation, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003380
    Speaking to a supportive audience, Bennett speaks about the upcoming election. He is critical about the Clinton administration, and he analyzes the Republican candidates.
    In the interview, Bennett speaks about the Heritage Foundation. He believes what makes Heritage stand out is that it gets behind a person. He calls it the most important conservative public policy organization. He feels very good about the conservative movement intellectually. However, he says the movement needs to get beyond analysis and start to offer solutions. He further calls for conservatives to ween themselves off federal money, giving an example of financial aid for college to middle-class Republicans.
  - Sound recording of Lee Edwards speaking about Walter Judd, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003982
    Edwards recounts various things about Walter Judd. The opposite side of the cassette features Edwards interviewing Judd.
  - Sound recording of the 1988 Conservative Political Action Conference Awards Banquest addresses, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003972
    Conservative Political Action Conference - 1988
    88363-160 Awards Banquet Address: Evans; Awards Recipients: Bork, Clancy, Judd
    Phyllis Schlafly speaks in lieu of Judge Bork.
  - Sound recordings of a discussion concerning publishing economics books, photographs of dignitaries, a day in the life of Walter Judd, and a discussion about China, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003591
    A discussion regarding economic affairs in several countries, book publishing, and books by economists. A name that comes up a few times is Ludwig von Mises. It seems to be a conversation about how to successfully publish and promote pro-free-market books, especially in Latin America.
    Side B of the cassette has three distinct parts. In the first part, Edwards discusses photographs of "Walter" with various foreign dignitaries, many from southeast Asia. In the second part, Edwards asks Walter Judd (definitely Judd in this section) to describe a day in his life while a Congressman. During the discussion, Edwards audibly notes the cassette recorder was running out of battery power, and the sound quality is therefore lacking. The third part is Edwards with an unknown, Asian speaker talking about China.
  - Sound recordings of an unidentified speech concerning human rights in China and Lee Edwards interviewing Louise Oliver on 11 Jan 2002, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004813
  - Sound recordings of interviews concerning the history of The Intercollegiate Studies Institute, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003375
    Interviewees: Steve Belch, Forrest McDonald, Eugene Meyer, Steve Calabresi
    The subject matter of these interviews is the conservative movement, especially its strides during the Reagan administration.
  - Ed Feulner speech on 12 Apr 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005388
    A talk on the Heritage Foundation.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Angela Antonelli on 17 May 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005361
    This interview concerns the Heritage Foundation and the Conservative movement of the 20th century.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Bob Moffett on 22 Mar 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005542
  - Lee Edwards interviews Chris DeMuth on 9 Sep 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005381
    This interview concerns think tanks, especially AEI and Heritage.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Dave Brown on 12 Apr 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005373
  - Lee Edwards interviews Dave Jones on 16 May 1992, 2 sound cassettes (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005534
    Edwards interviews Jones in preparation for Edwards' political biography of Barry Goldwater.
  - Lee Edwards interviews David Warren on 7 Jan 1999, 2.0 sound microcassettes (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005404
    This interview is about Grove City College, its history, and higher education in general.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Dusty Rhodes on 1 May 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005547
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ed Meese on 3 Apr 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005541
  - Lee Edwards interviews Fritz Rench on 12 Apr 1996, 2 sound cassettes (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005546
  - Lee Edwards interviews Grove City College trustees, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005526
    The trustees interviewed are Louise Slavcoff Baird, Harvey A. Miller, Richard M. Larry, unidentified male trustee (his name sounds like "Bill Klinderthan").
  - Lee Edwards interviews James Smith on 9 May 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005550
    This interview is about the Heritage Foundation, the Brookings Institution, and think tanks.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Jeff Gayner on 15 Apr 1996, 2 sound cassettes (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005390
  - Lee Edwards interviews Jim Przystup on 3 May 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005544
  - Lee Edwards interviews Kathy Rowan and Missy Stephens on 18 Jul 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005548
    Lee Edwards interviews Kathy Rowan and Missy Stephens in DC in research for his book on the Heritage Foundation.
  - Lee Edwards interviews M.E. Lewes on 2 Jul 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005539
    This interview concerns the Heritage Foundation, think tanks in America, and their impact on government policy.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Malcolm Scully on 7 Dec 1998, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005418
    This interview focuses on higher education. Conducting the interview while Edwards is researching his book on Grove City College, the interview focuses on the cost of school, tenure, size of colleges and universities, and the philosophies of academic intellectuals.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Michael Shuman on 29 Apr 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005549
    This interview concerns think tanks.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Pat Fagan on 3 Apr 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005387
    This interview concerns conservative politics, especially out-of-wedlock child birth.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Paul Sticht on 14 May 1999, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005411
    This interview concerns Grove City College and how the college is different in 1999 from when Sticht was in college. He frequently laments the social changes that have taken place over the years, for example the casuality of wearing hats in class.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Peg Miller on 8 Dec 1998, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005419
    Conducted during Edwards' research for his book on Grove City College, this interview concerns American higher education in general.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Rick Dearborn on 1 Apr 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005377
  - Lee Edwards interviews Scott Hodge on 5 Apr 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005532
    This interview focuses on the federal government of the early-mid 1990s.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Stanley Ikenberry on 8 Dec 1998, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005421
  - Lee Edwards interviews Stuart Butler on 16 Jul 1997, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005357
    Concerns the Heritage Foundation
  - Lee Edwards interviews Tom Atwood in 1997, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005366
  - Lee Edwards interviews Tom Atwood on 22 Mar 1996, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005362
  - Newt Gingrich speech: A Campaign About America, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005409
    The shell of a cassette asks the listener to "[c]opy this tape and share it with your family and friends."
  - Newt Gingrich speech: Freedom and Faith, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005417
  - Newt Gingrich speech: It's Morning in America--Again, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005521
    Gingrich reflects on the outcome of the 1996 congressional election and its implications for the nation, Republican Party, and GOPAC.
    The shell of a cassette asks the listener to "[c]opy this tape and share it with your family and friends.
  - Newt Gingrich speech: Keeping the Flame Alive, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005410
  - Newt Gingrich speech: Proclaiming Your Vision: Nine Strategies for Leading America, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005396
    In this GOPAC-produced cassette, Speaker Gingrich outlines his ideas for the future of America. The program is a recording of a speech the speaker gave to an audience.
  - Newt Gingrich speech: Visualize Victory: A Framework for the 1996 Campaign, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005397
    Speaker Gingrich outlines the themes and arguments of the 1996 campaign.
  - Sunday morning session with Lee Edwards on 30 Apr 1995, 1 sound cassette (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005385
    Edwards speaks about Barry Goldwater, Goldwater's 1964 presidential campaign, its legacy in 1995, and Goldwater's libertarian social views.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Alan Simpson on 28 Jul 1993, 1.0 sound open reel tape (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0008487
  - Lee Edwards interviews Barry Goldwater on 1 Jun 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005635
  - Lee Edwards interviews Barry Goldwater on 16 Dec 1991, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005625
    Edwards interviews Barry Goldwater on a day Goldwater was not feeling well.
    In addition to the main interview, following Goldwater, the cassette includes an unrelated Spanish program.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Barry Goldwater on 17 Dec 1991, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005626
    In addition to the main interview, following Goldwater, the cassette includes two unrelated programs.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Barry Goldwater on 26 Jun 1991, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005624
  - Lee Edwards interviews Bobby Inman on 6 Oct 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005660
  - Lee Edwards interviews Bud Mote on 11 Nov 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005667
  - Lee Edwards interviews Cokie Roberts on 2 Dec 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005675
  - Lee Edwards interviews Daniel Patrick Moynihan on 21 Jul 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005649
  - Lee Edwards interviews Denny Sharon on 18 Sep 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005658
  - Lee Edwards interviews Dodie London on 19 Apr 1994 and Ed McAteer on 3 May 1994, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005912
    The interview with Dodie London concerns Senator Barry Goldwater.
    The interview with McAteer concerns religion in politics and the founding of the Moral Majority.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Elizabeth Brown on 12 Nov 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005670
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ellen Thrasher on 7 Aug 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005654
    This interview concerns Senator Barry Goldwater
  - Lee Edwards interviews George Denison on 13 Oct 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005661
  - Lee Edwards interviews George McDonnell on 23 Dec 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005905
    This interview concerns the conservative movement and Senator Barry Goldwater.
  - Lee Edwards interviews John and Priscilla Stringer on 18 Nov 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005671
  - Lee Edwards interviews Junius Bowman on 4 Mar 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005638
    Lee Edwards interviews Junius Bowman about Senator Barry Goldwater.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Margo Carlisle on 29 Jun 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005642
  - Lee Edwards interviews Mary Vinovich on 22 Oct 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005662
  - Lee Edwards interviews Mike Goldwater on 4 Jan 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005907
  - Lee Edwards interviews Milton Friedman on 16 Dec 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005906
    Lee Edwards interviews Milton Friedman over the phone. The men discuss Friedman's involvement with Senator Barry Goldwater's 1964 campaign.
    The conversation occasionally touches on comparing Goldwater to Reagan. Related, Friedman says the biggest mistake of Reagan was reversing the legacy of 1964: taking the power away from "East Coast, country club" Republicans and giving it to the populist Western Republicans. Friedman argues a much better pick for a running mate over Bush would have been Donald Rumsfeld.
    At the end of the conversation, Friedman speaks about the term limits and balanced budget movements.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Phyllis Schlafly on 17 May 1994 and John Grenier on 1 Jun 1994, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005623
  - Lee Edwards interviews Richard Thompson on 7 Jul 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005648
    This interviews concerns Senator Barry Goldwater.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Sam Nunn on 15 Sep 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005655
  - Lee Edwards interviews Strom Thurmond on 1 Dec 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005674
  - Lee Edwards interviews Susan Goldwater on 23 May 1994, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005911
    This interview, conducted over the phone, concerns Barry Goldwater.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Trapper Drum on 1 Jul 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005645
  - Lee Edwards interviews Twinkle Thompson on 4 Aug 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005650
  - Lee Edwards interviews William Baroody, Jr. on 27 Oct 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005663
    This interview concerns Senator Barry Goldwater as well as Baroody's father.
  - Lee Edwards interviews William Brock on 28 Oct 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005665
  - Lee Edwards interviews William Quinn on 2 Oct 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005659
    Following the interview, Edwards forgets to shut off the recorder and one hears him walking to and driving in his car.
  - Sound recording of an ABC television program 20/20 on Barry Goldwater from 23 Jul 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005910
    This program focuses on Barry Goldwater's view on particular issues. It starts by focusing on how his views on gays in the military, abortion, and the religious right are in conflict with the contemporary Republican Party. Other issues include his relationship with President Clinton, his views on Congress, Japanese companies, Ross Perot, and Goldwater's legacy.
    It sounds like this sound recording was made by Edwards in his living room while he was watching the program. The sound quality is poor.
  - Undated sound recording of Leonard Liggio, 1 sound cassette (Box 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0005908
    Liggio, of the Institute for Humane Studies, speaks in Vienna, Virginia.
    An interview with Liggio follows on topics such as--but not limited to--libertarianism, conservatism, Murray Rothbard, and Ayn Rand.
- Incremental Materials (Box 331-347)
  - Reagan Presidential Library materials from Edwin Meese (Box 336-340)
- Incremental materials, films, and video recordings (Box 348-351)